https://case.edu/privacy-statement/index.html

Website Privacy Statement
This policy discloses the privacy practices for most websites within the case.edu/cwru.edu domain. Specific sites within the case.edu domain may have different privacy practices. If applicable, consult the privacy statement on each page.
We understand the privacy concerns of our website visitors. Case Western Reserve University collects information from visitors when they access case.edu to provide visitors with a better online experience with the university.
By using this website, you agree to abide by this Privacy Statement, the university’s Legal Privacy Notice as well as any other applicable University Technology policies.
Frequently Asked Questions
What information do we collect?
The university (including through third-party providers) may collect some identifiable information about how visitors access and use websites affiliated with the case.edu domain. This information includes IP address, browser, geolocation, device type and more. Cookies may be used to facilitate the navigation of this site, but these cookies do not contain information that alone can identify individuals.
The generic information collected by Case Western Reserve is based on IP address, which is the location of a computer or network. For admission and recruiting purposes, some IP addresses and cookies may be collected and stored; when used in conjunction with a third-party system, individuals' information may be identified. This information will not be used beyond admissions offices, unless required to do so by law. In most other instances, Case Western Reserve will not associate an IP address and/or web usage data with any other university information that could specifically identify a visitor, unless required to do so by law.
Some webpages within case.edu may also collect personal data through forms, surveys, event registration, newsletter subscriptions, etc. This information helps Case Western Reserve communicate with individuals who have expressed interest in receiving information from the university, such as registering for an event, submitting an application, etc.
What do we use your information for?
With non-personally identifiable information such as IP addresses, Case Western Reserve is able to:
Personalize and enhance visitors’ experiences,
Improve the website and/or
Help diagnose problems with the university’s server.
If a visitor fills out a form, completes a survey or subscribes to a newsletter using personal information, such as an email address, the email address provided may be used to send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.
How do we protect your information?
Case Western Reserve implements a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of visitors’ personal information, including the use of a secure server for private data, such as credit cards, Social Security numbers, etc. After a transaction is complete, private information is not stored on our servers.
Remember: No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100 percent secure.
Do we use cookies?
Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to a visitor’s computer's hard drive through his/her web browser that enables Case Western Reserve to recognize the browser, capture and remember certain information, such as user preferences, and collect aggregate data about site traffic.
Visitors may refuse the use of cookies by adjusting browser settings—though disabling cookies may prevent visitors from using the full functionality of some CWRU websites.
Cookies may be set by an organization other than Case Western Reserve, such as YouTube, Twitter, Facebook, Google Plus or other social media services for which the university has implemented “plug-ins.” Information on their cookie policies can be found on these sites directly.
Do we disclose any information to outside parties?
Case Western Reserve does not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer personally identifiable information gathered from website traffic to outside parties.
CWRU may share user information with third-party partners as necessary to provide and improve web services or other communications to users. Third parties who receive user information for this purpose are prohibited from using or sharing the data for any purpose other than providing services to users.
Information also may be provided to third parties in circumstances in which doing so is necessary or appropriate to: satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request; detect, prevent or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues; or protect the rights, property or safety of campus, users or others. Non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising or other uses.
Third-party links
Websites on case.edu often provide links to third-party websites as a convenience to users. Case Western Reserve University does not control third-party websites and is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of any linked-to, third-party websites or any hyperlink in a linked-to website.
Google Analytics
Many sections of case.edu use Google Analytics to help understand how visitors use the website. Through Google Analytics, the university can obtain visitors’ cookie data, such as the source, medium and IP address. This information is transmitted to and stored by Google on its servers. Google will use this information to evaluate visitors’ website use, compile reports on website activity, and provide other services relating to Internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google will not associate a visitor’s IP address with any other data held by Google. By using case.edu, visitors consent to Google’s data collection and processing.
Find more information on Google Analytics terms of use and privacy practices.
Advertising and Remarketing
Some parts of case.edu may use the Google AdWords or other third-party retargeting/remarketing services to advertise to previous visitors to the site through third-party websites. Such third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on someone's past visits to this website. Any data collected will be used in accordance with Case Western Reserve, Google and other third-party privacy policies.
Opt-out
You may opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads by visiting the Ads Preferences Manager. To opt out of other advertising and retargeting, email webteam@case.edu. You also can manage all of your browser's advertising preferences and, if desired, opt-out on the Network Advertising Initiative website.
Website Privacy Statement Only
This website privacy statement applies only to information collected through case.edu/cwru.edu, and not to information collected offline.
Terms and Conditions
Please also visit our Terms and Conditions page, which establishes the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of the website at case.edu/legal.html.
Changes to Our Privacy Policy
Changes to Case Western Reserve University’s website privacy policy will be posted on this page, and include an update to the policy date.
This policy was updated April 25, 2019.
Contact Us
If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy, email webteam@case.edu.
